Preliminary Inventory to the Metropolitan Council on Housing Records TAM.173
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive
Metropolitan Council on Housing Records
Bulk, 1959-1995
1939-2005, (Bulk 1959-1995)
TAM.173
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive
70.0 linear feet in 70 record cartons.
The Metropolitan Council on Housing was formed in 1959. Veteran housing activists associated with the left (notably the American Labor Party and the Communist Party) played a prominent role; these included Esther Rand and Jane Benedict, longtime MCH leaders. MCH has fought for increased public housing, the maintenance of rent control, and other housing priorities, using a range of tactics that included rent strikes and lobbying. The records contain subject and administrative files, and include clippings, correspondence, minutes and other internal documents, press releases, reports, printed ephemera, government documents, audiocassettes and videocassettes. NOTE: This collection is housed offsite and advance notice is required for use.
Metropolitan Council on Housing (New York, N.Y.).
Provenance
Donated by Metropolitan Council on Housing, 1995, 2002, 2008.
Access Restrictions
Open for research without restrictions.
Historical/Biographical Note
The Metropolitan Council on Housing was formed in 1959. Veteran housing activists associated with the left, notably the American Labor Party and the Communist Party played a prominent role, including Esther Rand and Jane Benedict, longtime MCH leaders. MCH has fought for increased public housing, the maintenance of rent control, and other housing priorities, using a variety of tactics, including rent strikes and lobbying. MCH is a membership organization, and also has chapters based on buildings. MCH publishes The Tenant/Inquilino and hosts a radio program on WBAI, "Listen to Housing Notebook." The organization's website is: http://www.metcouncil.net/ (accessed June 18, 2007).
Sources:
Ronald Lawson, ed. The Tenant Movement in New York City, 1904-1984(New Brunswick, N.J.: Rutgers University Press, 1986).
Scope and Content Note
The records, unprocessed as of this writing, contain subject and administrative files, and include clippings, correspondence, minutes and other internal documents, press releases, reports, printed ephemera, government documents, audiocassettes and videocassettes.
Arrangement
The collection is unprocessed. Series one and two are arranged alphabetically; the folders in series three are in the order in which they were received (no apparent system of arrangement); series four is arranged alphabetically within each box
The files are grouped into four series:
I, Administrative Files (9 linear ft.)
II, Subject Files (14 linear ft.)
III, 2002 Accession (38 linear ft.)
IV, 2008 Accession (8 linear ft.)
V, Audio
Related Material at the Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Eastside Tenants Council Records (Tamiment 253).
Roland Lawson Papers (Tamiment 214), relating to the history of New York Metropolitan Area housing issues and tenant activism.
Benedict, Jane; Cooper Square Committee.; East Side Tenants Council.; Goldin, Frances.; Metropolitan Council on Housing (New York, N.Y.). Community Improvement Fund.; Metropolitan Council on Housing (New York, N.Y.).; Morningsiders United.; National Tenants Organization.; Rand, Esther.; Riverside Edgecombe Neighborhood Association (New York, N.Y.).; Clippings (information artifacts); Community organization |z New York (State) |z New York.; Correspondence.; Government records.; Housing |z New York (State) |z New York.; Landlord and tenant |z New York (State) |z New York.; Minutes.; Municipal government records.; New York (N.Y.) |x Politics and government |y 1951-; Press releases.; Printed ephemera.; Public housing |z New York (State) |z New York.; Rent control |z New York (State) |z New York.; Rent strikes |z New York (State) |z New York.; Reports.; Squatters |z New York (State) |z New York.; State government records.
- Series I: Administrative Files., 9.0 linear feet
  Scope and Content Note
  This series includes executive board minutes, documents relating to MCH's workshops, its annual assemblies and conferences, and to the MCH Community Improvement Fund, files relating to housing code enforcement and fuel cost pass-along, and queries from tenants and tenant groups.
  - Anti-Eviction Committee: MCH committee, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Architects' Renewal Committee in Harlem (ARCH), MCH part of, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Assembly: MCH's annual assemblies, 1967-1988 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Assembly: MCH's annual assemblies, 1967-1988 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Assembly: MCH's annual assemblies, 1967-1988 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Assembly: MCH's annual assemblies, 1967-1988 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Benedict, Jane, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Black Panthers: MCH's work for BPP, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Borglum, Helen: Lawsuit: J. Benedict vs. Helen Borglum, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Branch Information Bulletin, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Brooklyn Freedom Democratic Movement: MCH's work for Major Owens' City Council campaign 1965 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Build Public Housing Committee: MCH committee to get public housing built on Rupert Brewery site, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Cadman Plaza: MCH's work to get public housing built on Cadman Plaza site 1963 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Committee Against Rent Increase Pass-alongs (CARIP): MCH-initiated coalition against rent increase pass-alongs, from 1981; includes papers from lawsuit against Rent Guidelines board (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Citywide Action Committee Against Homeless: MCH initiated coalition against warehousing, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - The City-Wide Council For Better Housing: precursor to MCH initiated by MCH founding organizations, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - City-Wide Tenants United: MCH initiated coalition, 1976? (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Code Enforcement: MCH's work on rent increases and code enforcement, 1963-1970 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Code Enforcement: MCH's work on rent increases and code enforcement, 1963-1970 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Code Enforcement: MCH's work on rent increases and code enforcement, 1963-1970 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Code Enforcement: MCH's work on rent increases and code enforcement, 1963-1970 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Committee To Save Our City's Homes: chaired by Jane Benedict; coalition against demolition, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Conference: MCH's annual conferences, 1962-1978 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Conference: MCH's annual conferences, 1962-1978 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Conference: MCH's annual conferences, 1962-1978 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Conference: MCH's annual conferences, 1962-1978 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Conference: MCH's annual conferences, 1962-1978 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Conference: MCH's annual conferences, 1962-1978 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Conference: MCH's annual conferences, 1962-1978 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Conference: MCH's annual conferences, 1962-1978 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Conference: MCH's annual conferences (NOTE: there are five additional folders on annual conferences in this box), 1962-1978 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Conference: MCH's annual conferences, 1961-1962 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Conference: MCH's annual conferences, 1961-1962 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Constitution Structure: MCH's constitution, adopted 1967 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Contracts: MCH's work on a model union-like contract for tenants, undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Convention 1983: MCH's 1983 convention (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Cooper Square: MCH's work on alternative plan for Cooper Square site, 1965-1985 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Cooper Square: MCH's work on alternative plan for Cooper Square site, 1965-1985 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Cooper Square: MCH's work on alternative plan for Cooper Square site, 1965-1985 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Cooper Square Community Development Committee: MCH's 1965 annual conference on Cooper Square site (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Court Cases: Amicus brief for MCH in Park West Village Associates vs Abrams, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Courtroom Committee: List of members, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Emergency Tenants Protection Act: MCH's work around this legislation, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Emergency Tenants Protection Act: MCH's work around this legislation, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Executive Board, 1973-1984 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Executive Board, 1973-1984 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Executive Board, 1973-1984 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Executive Board, 1973-1984 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Executive Board, 1973-1984 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Executive Board, 1973-1984 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Executive Board, 1973-1984 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Executive Board, 1959-1972 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Executive Board, 1959-1972 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Executive Board, 1959-1972 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Executive Board, 1959-1972 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Executive Board, 1959-1972 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Executive Board, 1959-1972 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Eyedent MCH amicus brief in demolition case, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Federation Of NY Tenant Organizations, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Flynn-Dearie, 1977-1989 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Flynn-Dearie, 1977-1989 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Flynn-Dearie, 1977-1989 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Flynn-Dearie, 1977-1989 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Flynn-Dearie, 1977-1989 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Flynn-Dearie, 1977-1989 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Flynn-Dearie, 1977-1989 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Flynn-Dearie, 1977-1989 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Flynn-Dearie, 1977-1989 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Foundation #2: Met Council Tenant Foundation, Inc, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Foundation #1: Met Council Community Improvement Fund, Inc.and Metropolitan Council Tenants Defense and Education Fund, Inc., 1966-1971 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Foundation minutes and membership, undated (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Foundation - Decent Housing For New York's People booklet, undated (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Foundation - Lindsey's Rent Increase Plan booklet, undated (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Fraud booklet published by MCH, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Fuel Cost Passalong: MCH's work against this rent increase program, undated (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Fuel Cost Passalong: MCH's work against this rent increase program, undated (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Fuel Cost Passalong: MCH's work against this rent increase program, undated (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Fuel Cost Passalong: MCH's work against this rent increase program, undated (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Fuel Cost Passalong: MCH's work against this rent increase program, undated (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Fund-Raising: Various MCH events, undated (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Heat (through 1981) MCH work on heat laws and enforcement (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - HRM: MCH's work against city program, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Joseph Hyler vice-chair of MCH, undated (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Independent Action Committee - MCH involved, undated (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - IN REM Organizational MCH's in rem committee, 1979-1981 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Invitations from other institutions (speaking), undated (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Kleiger Decision MCH's motion to intervene - HAD vs. CHIP, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Labor Cost Repeal Law MCH as party in lawsuit via CARIP, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Labor Cost Passalong: MCH's work against this rent increase program, 1970-1975 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Labor Cost Passalong: MCH's work against this rent increase program, 1970-1975 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Labor Cost Passalong: MCH's work against this rent increase program, 1970-1975 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Labor Cost Passalong: MCH's work against this rent increase program, 1970-1975 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Law Committee, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Law suits: Various, mid-80s, MCH party in, 1980s (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Leaflet originals, undated (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Membership, undated (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Membership, undated (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Membership, undated (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Membership, undated (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Membership Meeting, 1967 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Membership Ocean-Kings, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - MCH Community Improvement Fund, undated (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - MCH Community Improvement Fund, undated (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - MCH Community Improvement Fund, undated (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - MCH Community Improvement Fund, undated (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - MCH Community Improvement Fund, undated (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - MCH: General Publicity, undated (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - MCH: General Publicity, undated (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - MCH: Evaluation, 1959-1965 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - MCH: Policy and statements, undated (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Miscellaneous Buildings, undated (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Nominations Committee, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Nominations Committee, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Nominations, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Vici O'Mara - MCH board member, undated (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Organizing Committee 1977-current (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Organizer, The: MCH internal newsletter, undated (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Organizing handbook (MCH publication), 1971-1973 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Organizing handbook (MCH publication), 1971-1973 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Political Action, undated (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - People Outraged With Energy Rates (POWER): MCH involved, undated (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Press MCH op-eds, etc, undated (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Public Housing Committee, undated (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Public housing: 1967 Conference (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Public housing: Massive Public Housing, undated (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Public housing: MCH Program, undated (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Publicity: Clippings mentioning MCH, undated (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Public ownership, undated (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Queries, undated (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Queries, undated (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Queries, undated (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Queries, undated (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Queries, undated (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Queries, undated (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Queries, undated (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Queries, undated (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Queries, undated (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Queries, undated (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Queries, undated (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Queries, undated (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Esther Rand (Memorial Meeting), undated (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Esther Rand, undated (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Jack Rand, undated (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Rents into Repairs (see also Foundation), undated (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Songs, undated (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Spanish Organizing Committee, undated (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - William Stanley, undated (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Tenants, you are not alone, undated (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Times Square, 1986-1992 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Times Square Hotel #1, undated (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Times Square Hotel #2, undated (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - 25th Anniversary, undated (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Vacant Land Survey #1, undated (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Vacant Land Survey #2, undated (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - WBLS- Radio, undated (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - WBAI, undated (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - We Won't Move Committee (102nd St.- Don Erwin et. 21), undated (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - What is the Metropolitan Council on Housing? And similar pamphlets, undated (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Workshops, 1989 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Workshops, 1988 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Workshops, 1987 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Workshops, 1973 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Workshop Materials June 26, 1971-News Coverage #1 (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Workshop Materials June 26, 1971- News Coverage #2 (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Workshops: MCH, undated (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Your Home Is Your Hassle, undated (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - Youth Project, undated (Box 9, Folder 27)
- Series II. Subject Files., 14.0 linear feet
  This series contains files relating to Columbia University and its relations with Morningsiders United, Mitchell-Lama and other public housing, the National Tenants Organization, New York State housing legislation and related lobbying efforts, rent control and rent stabilization, the Unity Party, Tenant Unity Day, urban renewal, and warehousing.
  - Albany, 1976-1989 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Albany, 1976-1989 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Albany, 1976-1989 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Albany, 1976-1989 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Albany, 1976-1989 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Albany, 1976-1989 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Albany, 1976-1989 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Albany, 1976-1989 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Albany, 1976-1989 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Albany, 1976-1989 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Albany, 1976-1989 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Albany, 1976-1989 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Albany, 1976-1989 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Albany, 1976-1989 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Albany, 1976-1989 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Albany, 1976-1989 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Albany, 1976-1989 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Albany, 1976-1989 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Allerton Coops, undated (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Columbia Tenants Union, undated (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Columbia Tenants Union, undated (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Columbia University: includes Morningsiders United, undated (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Columbia University: includes Morningsiders United, undated (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Columbia University: includes Morningsiders United, undated (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Columbia University: includes Morningsiders United, undated (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Greater Flushing Tenants Council, undated (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Homefront, undated (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Hotels, undated (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Hotels, undated (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Housing For All, undated (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Housing Now, undated (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Listener's Action (later called Housing Now), undated (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Legislation, 1974-1988 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Legislation, 1974-1988 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Legislation, 1974-1988 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Legislation, 1974-1988 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Legislation, 1974-1988 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Legislation, 1974-1988 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Legislation, 1974-1988 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Legislation, 1974-1988 (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Legislation, 1962-1974 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Legislation, 1962-1974 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Legislation, 1962-1974 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Legislation, 1962-1974 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Legislation, 1962-1974 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Legislation, 1962-1974 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Legislation, 1962-1974 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Legislation, 1962-1974 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Legislation, 1962-1974 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Legislation, 1962-1974 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Legislation, 1962-1974 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Legislation, 1962-1974 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Legislation, 1962-1974 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Legislation, 1962-1974 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Joseph Mauri, undated (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Mitchell-Lama: includes files on developments, 1976-1982 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Mitchell-Lama: includes files on developments, 1976-1982 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Mitchell-Lama: includes files on developments, 1976-1982 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Mitchell-Lama: includes files on developments, 1976-1982 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Mitchell-Lama: includes files on developments, 1976-1982 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Mitchell-Lama: includes files on developments, 1976-1982 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Mitchell-Lama: includes files on developments, 1976-1982 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Mitchell-Lama: includes files on developments, 1976-1982 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Mitchell-Lama: includes files on developments, 1976-1982 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Mitchell-Lama: includes files on developments, 1976-1982 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Mitchell-Lama: includes files on developments, 1976-1982 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Mitchell-Lama: includes files on developments, 1976-1982 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Mitchell-Lama: includes files on developments, 1976-1982 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Mitchell-Lama: includes files on developments, 1976-1982 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Mitchell-Lama: includes files on developments, 1976-1982 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Mitchell-Lama: includes files on developments, 1976-1982 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Mitchell-Lama: includes files on developments, 1976-1982 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Mitchell-Lama: includes files on developments, 1976-1982 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Mitchell-Lama: includes files on developments, 1976-1982 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Mitchell-Lama: includes files on developments, 1976-1982 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Mitchell-Lama: includes files on developments, 1976-1982 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Mitchell-Lama: includes files on developments, 1976-1982 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Mitchell-Lama: includes files on developments, 1976-1982 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Mitchell-Lama: includes files on developments, 1976-1982 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Mitchell-Lama: includes files on developments, 1976-1982 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Mitchell-Lama: includes files on developments, 1976-1982 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Mitchell-Lama: includes files on developments, 1976-1982 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Mitchell-Lama: includes files on developments, 1976-1982 (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Mitchell-Lama: includes files on developments, 1976-1982 (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Mitchell-Lama: includes files on developments, 1976-1982 (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Mitchell-Lama: includes files on developments, 1976-1982 (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Mitchell-Lama: includes files on developments, 1976-1982 (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - Mitchell-Lama: includes files on developments, 1976-1982 (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - Mobilization Against Displacement, 1981 (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - Mobilization for Youth, undated (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - Model Cities, undated (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - Model Cities, undated (Box 14, Folder 23)
  - Modular Housing, undated (Box 14, Folder 24)
  - Mollen, Scott, undated (Box 14, Folder 25)
  - Moynihan, Daniel, undated (Box 14, Folder 26)
  - National Tenants Organization, undated (Box 14, Folder 27)
  - National Tenants Organization, undated (Box 14, Folder 28)
  - National Tenants Organization, undated (Box 14, Folder 29)
  - National Tenants Organization, undated (Box 14, Folder 30)
  - National Tenants Organization, undated (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - National Tenants Rights Project, undated (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - National Tenants Union, undated (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Neighborhood Save Our Homes Committee, undated (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - NY State Legislation Coalition, undated (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - NY State Tenants Organization, undated (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - No Heat No Rent Committee, undated (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - 104-76, undated (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Public Housing, undated (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Public Housing, undated (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Public Housing, undated (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Public Housing, undated (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Public Housing, undated (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Public Housing, undated (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Public Housing, undated (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Public Housing, undated (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Public Housing, undated (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Public Housing, undated (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - Public Housing: specific developments and years, undated (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Public Housing: specific developments and years, undated (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Public Housing: specific developments and years, undated (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Public Housing: specific developments and years, undated (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Public Housing: specific developments and years, undated (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Public Housing: specific developments and years, undated (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Public Housing: specific developments and years, undated (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Public Housing: specific developments and years, undated (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Public Housing: specific developments and years, undated (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Public Housing: specific developments and years, undated (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Public Housing: specific developments and years, undated (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Public Housing: specific developments and years, undated (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Public Housing: specific developments and years, undated (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Public Housing: specific developments and years, undated (Box 16, Folder 14)